Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
I am a stone.
I do not move.
Very slowly.
I put snow in my mouth.
then he won't
see my breath.
I take my time.
I let him come closer.
I have only one bullet.
I aim at his eye.
Very gently. my finger
presses on the trigger.
I do not tremble.
I have no fear.
I'm a big boy now.
Ready. Vassili?
Now. Vassili.
Fire!
Fire. Vassili!
Come on. pick your feet up.
Get on your feet.
Prepare to board the train.
You there. come along with me now.
This way. pal.
All civilians. get out!
Make way. let the civilians off.
This is a military convoy.
No one stays on board
but our valiant soldiers.
This is a convoy
to Stalingrad...
only for the soldiers
of the Red Army.
All aboard!
Autumn. 1942.
Europe lies crushed
beneath the Nazi jackboot.
The German Third Reich
is at the height of its power.
Hitler's armies are charging
through the heart of the Soviet Union...
towards the oil fields
of Asia.
One last obstacle remains.
A city on the Volga...
where the fate of the world
is being decided: Stalingrad.
Glorious comrade Stalin...
has ordered not another
step backwards.
The people of the Soviet Union
shall be free.
Go forward. comrades.
Not a step backwards!
Listen to these letters
sent by Russian mothers...
to their sons on the front.
"Volodya. my child.
I know that it's for our motherland...
"I know that it's for our motherland
that you are giving your life.
"Everyone here knows
that you will not fall back.
"Everyone here
is proud of you.
"Your father is dead.
Your brothers are dead.
Avenge us
on the hordes of fascists".
Nobody move!
Stay on the boat!
Get back or I'll shoot!
Back from the rails. or we shoot.
Shoot the traitors!
Come on. come on!
Move!
Come on. comrades.
come on!
Move. or you'll be shot!
Over here. stretcher!
The one with
the rifle shoots!
One out of two
gets a rifle.
The one without
follows him!
When the one
with the rifle gets killed.
the one who is following
picks up the rifle and shoots!
The one with
the rifle shoots!
The one without follows him!
When the one with
the rifle gets killed.
the one who is following...
picks up the rifle and shoots!
The one with
the rifle shoots!
- This way. now.
- The one without follows him!
Soldiers of the glorious
Red Army. from now on...
it is either victory
or death!
- Those who retreat will be shot.
- I need a rifle.
There will be no mercy
for cowards and traitors!
Achtung!
It's hopeless. comrades.
Get back!
Pull back!
Get back! Get back!
In the name
of the Soviet Union.
not a step backwards.
or we shoot.
No retreat!
Not a step back!
- No mercy!
- Deserters will be shot.
- Fire!
- Shoot the traitors!
Cowards will be shot!
No mercy for cowards!
Russians. surrender.
You will see your home again.
This is not your war.
Join your German comrades.
they understand your suffering...
and will care more for you
than your own officers.
who are only sending you
to your death.
The Third Reich
is not your enemy.
The enemy is bloodthirsty Stalin
and his Bolshevik camp.
who have stolen your land. who have
deported your father...
Fire!
You'll get us caught.
comrade Commissar.
With your permission.
- Which one should I aim at first?
- You should wait...
till there's an explosion.
- Do you know how to shoot?
- A little.
Don't shoot. Don't shoot.
He's looking at us.
Thank you.
comrade Commissar.
Danilov. political officer.
second class.
Twenty-first infantry.
"Vassili Zaitsev".
"On this day.
September the 20th. 1942.
"a shepherd boy from the Urals...
"Arrived in the city of Stalingrad.
on the banks of the Volga.
"His name is Vassili Zaitsev.
"Like thousands before him. he came
to answer comrade Stalin's call.
"Armed with a rifle. he quickly made
the fascist invader realize that...
"from now on he would be punished for
every step he took in the motherland;
that from here on.
the only way was back".
What do you think?
I think comrade Commissar's
been overgenerous.
Let me go!
By order of comrade Stalin.
no civilian can leave the city.
Get back!
Stand away.
or we will open fire.
Stand away!
Get back!
Get back or we shoot!
Back!
Keep back!
Make way for
comrade Stalin's envoy!
I carried out my orders.
I sent in
all of my boys.
But the Germans
engulfed us.
They have artillery.
aircraft. tanks.
- And me. what did I have?
- The sacred duty to resist!
I have to
report to the boss.
Perhaps you'd prefer
to avoid the red tape.
My name is...
Nikita Sergeyevich Kruschev.
I've come to take things
in hand here.
This city is not Kursk...
nor is it Kiev. nor Minsk.
This city is Stalingrad.
Stalingrad!
This city bears the name
of the boss.
It's more than a city.
it's a symbol.
If the Germans
capture this city.
the entire country
will collapse.
Now. I want our boys...
to raise their heads.
I want them to act like
they have balls!
I want them to stop shitting
their pants!
That's your job.
As political officers.
I'm counting on you.
You.
what's your suggestion?
Shoot all the other generals
who have retreated...
and their
chiefs of staff too.
M- Make some examples.
- D-D-Deport families of the deserters...
- Yeah. that's all been done.
Give them hope!
Here. the men's only choice
is between German bullets and ours.
But there's another way.
The way of courage.
The way of love
of the motherland.
We must publish
the army newspaper again.
We must tell magnificent stories.
Stories that extol...
sacrifice. bravery.
We must make them believe
in the victory.
We must give them hope.
pride. a desire to fight.
Yes. we need to
make examples.
But examples to follow.
What we need...
are heroes.
Do you know any heroes
around here?
Yes. comrade.
I know one.
That's me!
"Vassili Zaitsev".
No. you're not dreaming.
It's your name.
We made the front page.
They haven't changed a word.
Do you have any idea
what this means?
It's not the back page.
it's not the second page.
- it's the front page.
- The front page!
They're going to reprint
our article everywhere.
In the Caucasus. in the Crimea.
even in the Urals.
Tomorrow morning. Stalin himself
will be sitting over breakfast.
reading my words.
memorizing your name.
We're famous. Vassili.
Kruschev loved the article.
He's promoted me
to the general staff.
And you
to sniper division.
- Well. that's good.
- It's very good.
- It's very good. It's great.
- It's very great!
- It's great!
- For us because we did it together.
Together!
- Although I did all the hard work.
- Oh. yeah?
- You're very lucky I can't fight back.
- Why's that?
Because Kruschev told me to make sure
nothing happens to you.
- You're too important.
- I'm too valuable.
Yes. careful of my... careful
of my glasses. please. They're new.
Sorry. sir.
- I'm famous! We're famous!
- I'm famous! I'm famous!
Vassili.
the young shepherd from the Urals.
killed his 12th
German officer today.
He used to hunt wolves.
now he shoots fascists.
Today. Vassili Zaitsev
shot his 23rd German officer.
He is an example to us all.
Vassili shot
his 32nd German officer.
Count only the Germans
you have killed.
- Today. Vassili Zaitsev...
- Here is the evidence...
11 dog tags retrieved
by sniper Vassili Zaitsev.
More and more men and women. fighters
from all branches of our armed forces.
join the sniper division and learn
the skills of Vassili Zaitsev.
I am a stone.
I breathe slowly.
I aim at the eye.
So it is you.
the great Vassili Zaitsev.
- My mother makes potatoes with bacon.
- Sounds good.
When she sees you.
she won't believe her eyes.
- How many today?
- Only two.
And the last one.
why didn't you shoot him?
He was only a foot soldier.
Wasn't worth giving away my position.
Bless you.
We know how much
we owe you.
We pray for you every day.
Every evening. we listen to them talk
about you on Radio Moscow.
Thanks. You've certainly
managed well down here.
My parents used to store furniture
down here before the war.
Sacha. drop that right now.
It's loaded.
This way. comrade Commissar.
Thank you. comrade.
Good evening.
Comrade Zaitsev?
My God. where does
all this mail come from?
From all over the country.
Mrs. Filipov. from all over.
This one's from the workers
of the Kouzbass.
They want to name
their mine after Vassili.
Right. let's start
with the miners.
Come on.
let's get to work.
Dear comrades
from the Kouzbass.
- Kouzbass.
- I thank you for your letter of praise.
- Praise?
- R-A-I-S-E.
And... I hope that
I can live up...
to your expectations...
A- T-I-O-N-S.
Expectations.
You're interested
in German literature. Mrs. Filipov?
It's all right.
it's our neighbor.
- Right. where were we?
- Tania. we have guests.
Your offer to name...
I...
I- I recognize you.
He's Vassili Zaitsev.
I saw your picture
in the paper.
Thank you
for everything you're doing.
- And this is his friend. Commissar...
- Danilov.
Danilov.
Tania is like
a daughter to me.
She used to take care of Sacha
when I worked at the factory.
She even taught him German.
All these books are hers.
- Oh. they're yours?
- She studied German at the university.
- Which university?
- Moscow.
Moscow. Moscow.
Shouldn't we. uh...
Yes. let's continue.
Your offer to name
your mine after me...
is... a great honor.
H- O-N.
Yes. I know.
Honor.
Very good.
Shouldn't we make the point that
I'm not the only one fighting?
That... That's excellent...
excellent idea. Vassili.
- We can take it even further though.
- Oh.
We can take it further.
Your battle for
the production of coal...
is as worthy as mine.
There's no "K" in coal.
Just-Just one "L."
Oh. tell me if I'm going too fast.
- No. you're not going too fast.
- You sure?
I just thought is there
any other improvements?
Why don't you get some rest?
These letters can wait until tomorrow.
We should carry on.
We're not tired.
Thank you. Mrs. Filipov.
These people...
took the trouble
to write to us.
Tomorrow. we may not
be around to write back.
Major Konig.
Herr General.
I was expecting
someone...
else.
Certainly not someone
so prestigious.
I imagine you have
your reasons...
for getting yourself involved
in this hellish situation.
My army is not designed
for this kind of fighting.
Yesterday. yet again.
I had to promote...
25 sergeants to replace the officers
shot down by their sharpshooters.
Those snipers are
demoralizing my people.
This city is no more than...
a heap of ruins.
But the fuehrer's persisting.
He has made it a personal matter
between Stalin and himself.
We should trust
the fuehrer's instinct.
He always managed to
lead us to victory.
We shall be back home
for Christmas.
How are you going to go about finding
this young Russian?
I'll fix it so that he's the one
who finds me.
Vassili.
- Come on. time to get up.
- What?
They have a problem in the department
store sector. They need us. Come on.
Look. Vassili. he's hiding
in the department store. Over there.
So far this morning.
he's knocked off five officers.
plus two machine gunners.
Look. third floor.
fourth window from the left.
Fourth window from the left.
See him?
Yeah. I see him.
There. you got him!
Great shot.
Let's go get
his dog tag.
Good-bye. comrade Commissar.
Thank you for your
hospitality. Mrs. Filipov.
You can borrow
whatever you like.
I'm not sure what they would say
to me at headquarters...
if I came back with an armful
of Goethe and Schiller.
There's some Marx too.
You were assigned to civil defense
at the 12th district?
No. I volunteered.
It's such a coincidence
meeting you like this.
Comrade Kruschev was
telling me just yesterday...
how desperately we're in need
of operators who speak German.
I can't. Our militia's responsible
for all the people in this neighborhood.
We're already
desperately short of men.
We'll give you a dozen soldiers
for every one that speaks German.
I'd rather stay and fight.
Serving at headquarters is fighting.
You'd be far more useful there.
You stay here.
You cover us.
- All right.
- We go.
Take care.
Ludmilla. come on.
Check the stairway.
It's a trap.
I know.
Move back.
He's still here.
- They're coming straight for us!
- Ludmilla.
stay where you are.
he's over there somewhere.
We have to
get out of here!
- We have to get out of here!
- Just stay where you are!
What are we gonna do?
Ludmilla. stay where you are!
Fuck this. I'm going.
Ludmilla. no!
What does this mean?
"The little shepherd from the Urals
receives a new sniper's rifle.
"a Mosin-Nagant 7.62.
with its 3.5-Power P.U. Telescope.
Pride of precision
of Soviet production".
- I've seen that rifle close up.
- Have you?
I've even touched it.
I know him well. Vassili Zaitsev.
Ludmilla and Anton were killed today.
and it was my fault.
No. I'm sure
that's not true.
There was a German sniper.
I walked them right into his trap.
- What else can you tell me?
- He didn't relocate.
A sniper who doesn't
relocate isn't normal.
He was very good. It wasn't just
his shooting. it was his instinct.
He was a step ahead
of me all the time.
That's because he knows
everything about you.
His name is Konig.
Major Konig.
They've sent him here
to ki...
to find you.
At first we weren't sure
if the information was reliable.
It seems he's come
all the way from Berlin to stop you.
You've caused them so many sleepless
nights. they sent their top marksman.
- What do we know about him?
- He's a major in the Wehrmacht.
He's director of their
sniper school in Zossen.
Koulikov studied under him
at Zossen before the war.
He knows all his tricks. From now on.
he'll go with you everywhere.
A nobleman from Bavaria
who hunts deer...
against a shepherd boy from the Urals
who poaches wolves.
It's more than a confrontation
between two nations.
It's the essence
of class struggle.
I'm glad
you're so happy.
He had all the advantages.
Next time you'll be even.
No one shoots
like you. Vassili.
She's been transferred.
I'll see if they're ready
for you next door.
- Hello.
- You look smart in your new uniform.
Make sure they don't take it back
once you've finished.
Yeah. they probably will.
I've heard the rumor about the German.
and I wanted to wish you luck.
Thank you.
I'll need it.
From what comrade Danilov
tells me. you're going to win.
Hmm.
It's time.
- Vassili! Vassili!
- Come to my arms.
Look in my direction.
Put your cap back on.
you look more heroic.
- This way. comrade Zaitsev.
- I love this little fellow.
Vassili. is it true that
you volunteered for the front?
How old are you. Vassili?
Do you know what this duel
means for our country?
Is it true you killed your first wolf
when you were five?
Are you proud to be challenged
by the best sharpshooter in Germany?
The Germans are starting
to shit their pants.
Go on. my boy. tell us how
you're going to deal with him.
- Or rather. no. Tell it to the boss.
- One more question. please.
He likes
good hunting stories.
Look at him with pride.
because he's looking at you.
The whole country
is looking at you.
Forgive me. forgive me.
Grandfather.
So. it's not the wolf that
chooses the hunting ground...
but the hunter.
But I'm sure your grandfather
taught you that.
Except in this case.
I'm the game.
However.
today what we're going to do...
is lure the wolf
out of his lair...
to where we want him to be.
You're the one whose life is valuable.
You go first.
No. no. We take it in turns.
Next time is your turn to go first.
and then it's you. Volodya.
Son of a bitch!
These are new pants. I just took them
off a captain from the 251 st yesterday.
Sixteen months I spent
in Germany at the school in Zossen.
Of course. those were the days
when we were friends with the Krauts;
when our Joseph
and their Adolph...
were walking hand in hand.
From here to the wire.
160 meters. right?
One hundred and fifty-five.
Whatever. That'll make 'em
send out a repair guy.
Let's relocate.
Aah!
Hey. Volodya!
After the Germans
invaded us.
it wasn't the same
atmosphere anymore.
Threw my ass
in prison.
What were you doing
in Germany. huh?
Excuse me. says I. but it was
comrade Stalin who sent me there.
Don't bring our glorious leader
into your treachery.
Confess. spy bastard!
Confess.
And bang! Bang. bang. bang!
Well. there wasn't a sickle.
but there was a hammer.
And bang.
Knocked out all my teeth.
That's right. boy.
Have no illusions.
That's the land of socialism
and universal bliss for you.
Hey! It's your repair guy.
I got him.
It's about soup time.
isn't it?
I'm going.
Well. get a move on. Volodya.
and try not to spill it all
on your way back. you Marxist bastard.
The enemy sniper activity reported
during the past 24 hours. Herr Major.
Two sentries shot
in the train station sector.
One artillery observer
in the Northern sector.
One lieutenant from the 24th Panzer
division in the factory sector.
Three telephone repairmen
in the workers'housing sector.
They also tell me we have just taken
a prisoner who may interest you.
I hope he's still
able to speak.
Excuse me. sir?
Nothing.
Thank you.
So. tell us. Volodya.
which building is he in?
There is no way
I know that.
He moves around
all the time.
He jumps from one
to the next.
On which floor?
I don't know.
We'll see about that.
Undress him.
Put him in
one of our uniforms.
You see. they are stubborn.
That's the good thing
about the Germans.
Man. you got to admit
when they get an idea in their heads...
Right.
Let's see if our customer
has arrived.
Are you ready?
Uh-huh.
And now our famous shepherd
from the Urals.
who Major Konig
thinks is an idiot.
gets up to make sure
he has hit his target.
Major Konig sees him.
Aims for his helmet.
Fires.
Reveals his position
and is shot in turn.
Except...
Major Konig doesn't fire...
because Major Konig
isn't there.
Koulikov!
Don't you think that was strange.
that last one?
They sent him out
to get shot like the others.
It's not natural.
Not without artillery.
without trying to cover him.
Oh. no. I'm the one
who was stupid.
They don't give a shit
about telephone guys.
I mean. it's like us
with the Ukrainians.
They'd never bother a major
over a few dead grunts.
Tomorrow. we'll kill us
some generals.
Whose turn is it?
Mine. I think.
Oh. you're such a cheater!
You can't fool Papa Koulikov.
No. no. no. no. no. no. no.
it's my turn to go first.
And it's your turn to get a hole
in your britches.
To victory.
This sniper business
has been dragging on too long.
What's that little fellow
of yours up to?
He's probing.
comrade Kruschev.
He's testing the Germans
for weaknesses.
He's meticulous
in his preparation.
Vodka...
is a luxury we have.
Caviar is
a luxury we have.
Time is not.
He's aware of that
comrade Kruschev. We both are.
I assure you
he will succeed.
Good.
It seems your destinies
are entwined.
They're keeping you busy.
I picked this up
in the kitchen.
It's from the reception the other day.
I thought Mrs. Filipov might like it.
Um. she will be thrilled.
That's very sweet of you.
There's plenty more
if you're hungry.
You're Jewish.
aren't you?
There's nothing in our religion
that says you can't eat sturgeon.
My father had a premonition
all this would happen.
You mean the war?
He understood that the hatred
of the Jews ran deep.
He was saving up to buy
some land in Palestine.
He said it was the only land
we truly belonged in;
the only land
we had a duty to defend.
He insisted I learn
to use a rifle.
I learned to shoot.
I know that in times of war. personal
feelings should be put aside. but...
I have a favor
to ask you.
Of course.
Anything you want.
I want to be reassigned.
What's happened. Tania?
He shot him.
He shot him even though
he jumped first.
Shot him on the run.
It was
an impossible shot.
I've never seen
anything like it.
You've promised people
a victory I can't deliver.
I don't stand a chance
against this man.
You mustn't talk
like that. Vassili.
What if I told you we found
a way to track his movements?
We've got someone. Vassili.
Someone close to him
passing us information.
Next time you will be
one step ahead of him.
I promise.
Now I have a favor to ask.
From me?
It's about Tania.
Come in.
He doesn't even know you exist.
But at that moment. you are closer
to him than anyone else on earth.
You see his face
through the sight.
You see whether he shaved
that morning or not.
You can see whether he's married
by whether he has a wedding ring on.
It's not like...
just firing at a distant shape.
not just a uniform.
It's a man's face.
Those faces don't go away.
They come back and they just...
they get replaced by more faces.
Did Danilov ask you
to tell me this?
He likes you very much. I think he'd try
anything to change your mind.
Did he tell you
why I asked for the transfer?
No.
This morning. a list
arrived at headquarters.
It was a list of civilians
who'd been...
rounded up and sent to Germany
in a convoy...
that left Stalingrad
three weeks ago.
My parents
were amongst them.
After 30 kilometers.
the German soldiers...
stopped the train
and forced everyone out.
In the middle of a bridge.
they bound them together.
two by two.
Mothers with daughters.
Husbands and wives.
They... lined them up
against the railing.
and then they fired
a single shot at each pair...
to save bullets.
It worked.
The bodies of the ones who died
dragged the others under the water.
I know they died together.
They never would have let
themselves be separated.
That's Koulikov's rifle.
It's a good... rifle.
Thank you.
I know how he leaves
the shelter.
He goes through
the tractor factory.
The tractor factory is big.
I know exactly where.
He crawls through a gutter.
under a grate
where the vats are.
then he goes out
from the workshop.
In between the two.
there's a place where he's in the open.
It's under
a long. iron foot walk.
Good luck. comrade.
I know exactly where
he's waiting for me.
He'll be on the foot walk
over the gutter.
We'll take him out
from behind.
We'll get to the other end
of the workshop through these pipes.
Follow me.
You go that way.
I'll go around this way.
Okay?
Shit!
Sergei.
you should go back.
- No. I'll be all right.
- Go back.
No. you go!
Keep your legs in.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Comrade Stalin is asking for
one last effort!
The fate of the motherland
is at risk!
The fate of all those
you love and cherish!
It's for them
that we fight today.
Listen to me. Tania. The Germans
are throwing everything at us.
If they're lucky. one in ten
of these soldiers will come back alive.
You're highly educated.
You know languages.
Every intercept you translate
saves hundreds of lives.
Every message you decode
kills thousands of theirs.
You have a duty to survive.
Vassili was born to fire a gun.
It's what he knows.
You and I were born
for a different purpose.
If Vassili were here.
he would tell you the same thing.
Where is he?
Where is Vassili?
Keep your head down.
- Tell me where he is.
- Stay into that pipe. Tania.
Stay in. Stay in!
Get your head in!
Slow down.
Don't shoot.
He's over there.
Do you see the pillar
in front of you?
I need you
to move round behind it.
Go.
Tania. I need you to find
a large piece of glass.
Piece of glass.
Do you see the kiln...
behind me to the left
of the factory?
Yes? I can't hear you.
- Yes.
Do you see...
the two louvers?
- Yes.
- Do you see the one...
with a broken slat?
Yes.
This is what
I want you to do.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
Three... two... one...
Hello. Sacha.
He was right
where you said he'd be.
Nearly there.
He's very clever.
Tell me about him.
Why was it his grandfather taught him
how to shoot and not his father?
His father's dead.
His mother too.
Does he talk
about his father?
No. He didn't know him.
Did he go to school?
He knows how to write.
He answers lots of letters.
Hmm. Is it girls
who write to him?
Everyone writes to him.
Is there a girl
he loves in his village?
- Not in his village. here.
- Does she love him?
Yes. because he's handsome.
Because he's brave
and she's very beautiful.
I know her well.
She's from my neighborhood.
She went to the university.
They're handsome together.
Later. the two of them
will get married.
At least. I think so.
And you. Sacha.
why are you helping
the Germans?
Because they're stronger.
Because they're going to win the war.
And because you like
chocolate. huh?
All these people here
know they're gonna die.
So each night
when they make it back.
it's a bonus.
Excuse me.
So. every cup of tea.
every cigarette...
becomes a little celebration.
Because for a lot of us.
it may be our last night.
It's just something
you have to accept here.
Everyone has their time.
In the forest.
the wolf lives for three years.
the donkey for nine.
So. that's-that's got to be
a proverb from the Urals.
It makes no sense to me
whatsoever.
The donkey lives longer
because he's more useful.
Makes absolute sense.
There aren't any donkeys
in the forest.
You made it up.
So... I'm a donkey?
People like you
and Danilov...
have to survive this.
People who have read books.
had an education.
We'll need you
when the war is over.
And if you survive?
What will the useless
Vassili Zaitsev do then?
I wanna work in a factory.
My granddad took me
to a factory once.
There was this man there.
high up on a...
on a foot walk.
He wasn't wearing blue
like the others.
The people he was supervising
didn't understand what they were doing.
But for him.
for him up there.
it was simple;
it was clear.
And I thought. "One day.
I could be that man".
Sad to have a dream
you know won't happen.
Why shouldn't it?
You'll outlive us all.
Hmm.
You'll be the oldest donkey
in the forest.
"150 meters stand between
the Germans and the Volga.
"Today the whole world
is watching these 150 meters.
They are what makes
Stalingrad..."
the capitol...
of the war.
Your friend. Tania...
have you see her?
She stays over there now.
with the snipers.
Tell the major we're sending in
all of our sharpshooters...
to support the attack
on the factory.
Tell him Vassili
will be there.
- I need to talk to you.
- Sure.
- Danilov.
- Hmm?
You have to
stop writing about me.
I'm not gonna get him
because I'm not good enough.
Sooner or later. he's gonna find me.
he's gonna kill me.
I've warned you before
not to talk like this.
This time it's different.
You've built me up...
and up into someone I'm not.
I can't carry that weight anymore.
I wanna fight.
I want to fight just
as a regular soldier.
I understand.
The thing is. you're not a regular
soldier. You're extraordinary.
No. I'm what
you've made me.
Nothing more.
Why are you
telling me this now?
Hmm? What's happened?
What's changed?
Did you speak
to Tania for me?
- Yes.
- Well...
will she reconsider?
I don't know.
She should. She'll be much safer.
She should. you know that.
- Yeah.
- It'll be easier to get her reassigned.
The Germans are preparing
another offensive in the city center.
The propaganda battle is crucial
for morale. We need you more than ever.
Sacha. Hold on. Sacha!
- Tell him what you know. Sacha.
- Hello. Sacha.
There was dust
on the major's boots.
Sacha has the major convinced
he's gone over to the other side.
I don't need to tell you
the risks he's taking.
The dust was yellow. There's only
one place where there's dust like that...
in the back of the chemical factory.
a big heap on the tracks.
Well done.
Sacha...
wait for me outside then.
- Danilov.
- Hmm?
You had no right
to use him.
No. no. I didn't use him.
Vassili.
He did it of his own accord.
You know why?
Because he believes in you!
Tomorrow morning. we're going
to take back the chemical factory.
Sacha's informed the major
you'll be there.
so now you know where
you have to wait for him.
- In the middle of an assault.
- I'm following orders.
I suggest you do the same.
Now. I'm aware
of the risks.
You'll be fine.
Comrade.
That's the Germans
up there.
And yesterday
was the Russians.
We're not very far now.
Sacha...
you're playing
a very dangerous game.
I want you to win.
See there?
Keep going along the river.
It's safe... for a while.
He's dead.
We found this on his corpse.
Your reason for being here
has ceased to exist.
Pardon me. Herr General.
but I do not believe...
There is a plane bound for Berlin
tomorrow evening.
You will be on it.
Until then. I must ask you
for your dog tags.
Imagine how Russian propaganda
would profit from your death.
If you fall.
you will fall unknown.
You've already had
a near miss.
Also please take
this War Merit Cross.
It was awarded posthumously...
to a lieutenant of the
116th Infantry Division...
who fell here during the first days
of the battle.
He was my son.
If the landing is captured.
everything's lost!
Come here.
What did I tell you?
You've been playing
your fiddle too much!
If it's confirmed
that he's dead. we're sunk!
- Well. you're sunk.
- It isn't true.
It was intercepted
from their staff headquarters.
What do they have to do.
dangle his body in front our our men?
They're lying.
That's good.
Very good.
Write it. then.
"Vassili Zaitsev is not dead.
"This is what he had
for breakfast this morning.
This is a picture of him reading
today's newspaper". You're the poet.
What?
You won't give up
the riverbank!
I don't care if you've lost
half your men!
Lose the other half.
or lose yourself!
Is he back?
He should be back soon.
The German attack cut the lines.
That's why he's late.
Can we go outside?
I wrote to my mother
about you.
She wanted me to tell you
that once this war was over.
if there's anything you needed...
anything at all...
our family
will be there for you.
You know I'm here for you.
They're saying
Vassili is dead.
Vassili Zaitsev
will never see his loved ones again.
Surrender!
This is your only hope.
You're upset.
Because Zaitsev is dead?
You don't have to hide it.
There's no shame in it.
You're a Russian
like he is.
Don't listen to them.
It's just propaganda.
He isn't dead.
And do you know why?
Because I haven't
killed him yet.
I'm going to tell you
a little secret.
Only you. because
I know I can trust you.
But you must swear to me that
you won't tell another soul.
You swear?
I found a terrific spot.
It's by the exit
from the train station.
I'll hide
in the water tower.
Tomorrow.
I'll wait for him there.
You'll see.
He'll be there.
He always is.
I also want you to swear that from now
on. you'll stay home where you belong.
Do you swear?
Yes?
Good.
"We know he's alive.
We know he won't fail us.
We know because he is a part of us now.
Vassili is eternal".
Where have you been?
We've looked everywhere for you.
Oh. didn't you hear?
I was dead.
At least the noble sniper
Zaitsev...
Vassili was dead.
The real one.
Me...
I was asleep.
and I missed my chance.
Then. I was curled up
in a corner. hiding...
from a man
who wants to kill me.
I'll talk to Kruschev.
He'll send you back
to your old division.
- Where's Tania?
- She's at the shelter.
I've been to the shelter.
I told her you weren't dead.
The major said so.
He said the other Germans were lying.
He told me you were waiting
for him at the station.
Vassili.
My little Sacha.
I knew it.
- Vassili.
- Tania.
I knew you weren't dead.
How?
Because we only just met.
I prayed for the first time
since I was a little girl.
When I opened my eyes.
Sacha was standing there...
waiting to give me
the good news.
I think he loves you
even more than I do.
To the proper military authority.
I'm calling to the commandant's
attention the recent changes noticed...
in the attitude towards fighting
of soldier Vassili Zaitsev.
He has attempted on several occasions
to escape his duties.
voiced doubts on the chances
of our victory...
and made defeatist comments
in public.
The inexplicable
duration of his duel...
with the Nazi sharpshooter
can only be explained by...
his lack of belief
in the communist ideal.
Good morning. Sacha.
Once again. he knew
exactly where to find me.
Don't you think
that's strange?
Apart from me. only you knew.
I don't hold it against you.
Sacha.
You've done
a very brave thing.
You've chosen your camp.
I respect that.
But it isn't my camp.
We're both soldiers.
and we're both enemies.
so I know you understand.
I'm annoyed with you. little Sacha. for
not staying home as I made you swear to.
I'm annoyed with you for obliging me
to do what I'm going to have to do.
I've never seen anyone
frown so much in their sleep.
How long have you been
watching me?
All night.
You've been snoring away
happily for hours.
I don't snore.
Do I?
Like a pig.
I suppose I talk
in my sleep as well.
Yes.
There's something
I should tell you.
On the train...
coming here...
we were in the same car.
No.
I saw you.
You were reading.
and you fell asleep.
I didn't dare look at you.
you were so beautiful.
It was scary.
Afterwards. I couldn't stop
thinking about you.
It made me smile.
And then I thought of all the men
who would get to hold you...
who'd make you laugh...
how lucky they were.
And now I'm the one
lying next to you.
- Was I snoring?
- Like a pig.
What?
- Oh. my God!
- Oh. no.
- Tania. no.
- Tania. no!
- No. get off me!
- Get off me! Get off me!
- It's what he wants!
- This is what he wants!
- Get off me!
- No. he'll kill you. He'll kill you!
- Let me go!
- I'll run after you. and he'll kill me.
- This is what he wants! I'll get him.
I promise I'll get him.
I'll get his rifle for you.
I promise. Tania.
I need you.
You have to leave now. Mrs. Filipov.
Stalingrad may fall.
The last of the boats are leaving.
The Germans will be here any moment.
He's brought you a pass.
You'll be safe on the other side.
Gather your things. and we'll help you
carry them to the landing stage.
I'm not leaving.
This is my home.
This is my Sacha's home.
I can't leave.
I have to tell you something.
Mrs. Filipov.
Something very difficult
to understand.
It's about Sacha.
He's gone over to the Germans.
He's betrayed his country.
He's with the enemy now.
He won't be coming back.
Oh. my God.
He's become a traitor.
The poor little thing.
What has he done?
So. he's going to
stay over there?
Yes... he's going to
stay over there.
I shouldn't be saying this.
comrade Commissar.
but maybe
it's for the best.
If the Germans have won.
he'll be safe.
I know it's wrong. but perhaps
he has made the right choice.
- Oh! Oh. Tania!
- Tania?
- Oh. Tania!
- Tania!
Oh. my God! Oh!
I need a doctor!
A doctor!
I have a pass.
I have a pass!
You must let her cross.
Please!
- It's useless. She'll never make it.
- No! No. she will!
She's my daughter!
- I beg of you!
- All right.
- Oh. thank you!
- Put this one on the boat.
Where is he?
Where's the major?
A few inches
from your face.
I've been such a fool.
Vassili.
Man will always be man.
There is no new man.
We tried so hard to create
a society that was equal.
where there'd be nothing
to envy your neighbor.
But there's always
something to envy.
A smile...
a friendship.
Something you don't have
and want to appropriate.
In this world...
even a Soviet one...
there will always
be rich and poor.
Rich in gifts...
poor in gifts.
Rich in love...
poor in love.
Tania isn't coming back.
She's dead. Vassili.
She was cut down by shrapnel.
It was quick.
I don't think
she even saw it coming.
She was on her way
back to you.
As soon as she had seen Mrs. Filipov to
the boats. she was coming back for you.
She was right.
You're a good man. Vassili.
I want to help you.
Vassili.
Let me do one last thing.
Something useful
for a change.
Let me show you
where the major is.
Don't do that.
Don't do that!
Today. February 3. 1943.
is an ominous day for Hitler...
and the endless columns of hundreds
of thousands of German prisoners.
It is an unforgettable day
of hope for our motherland.
After 180 days of heroic combat...
in the market city
of Stalingrad.
and as a result of the valor
and self-sacrifice of our soldiers.
the commander
of our glorious Red Army...
received
the unconditional surrender...
of the German fascist invaders.
Sorry. No. young man.
I cannot find...
- a matching name in the book.
- Could you check again?
- This is the address and her name.
- She is not here.
Yes. this is our address.
but we don't have her anymore.
- This is the address. She's been here.
- I'm so sorry.
- She wrote to me.
- I looked three times. She's not here.
Believe me. there is no Tania Chernova.
I can't help you.
I'm so sorry.
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm